Guide to the Katherine Heinemann Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Katherine Heinemann papers
1920-1979
YCAL MSS 412
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
The Katherine Heinemann Papers contains correspondence, interview notes and sound recordings, photographs, notes, and clippings.
Heinemann, Katherine
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Katherine Heinemann, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for information about reference copies.
Katherine Heinemann
Katherine Heinemann, American poet. Heinemann was born in St. Louis and attended Washington University.
Scope and Contents
The Katherine Heinemann Papers contains correspondence, interview notes and sound recordings, photographs, notes, and clippings.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives.; Audiovisual materials.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Heinemann, Katherine
- Correspondence
  - Boyle, Kay, 1975-1979; 2 (Box 1)
  - Bryher, Winifred, 1977 (Box 1)
  - MacLeod, Norman, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Marissael, Grace McAlmon, 1975-1976; 2 (Box 1)
- Interviews
  - Notes on interview with Kay Boyle, undated (Box 1)
  - Interview with P.J. Hutson - niece of R., 1978 October 20; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002104888657)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Notes on interview with Grace McAlmon Marissael, 1975, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Interview with Grace McAlmon Marissael in El Paso at my home (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1976 March 9; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002104888673)
    Related Materials
    This audiocassette is related to a folder of material titled "Notes on interview with Grace McAlmon Marissael" in Box 1.
  - Interview with Grace McAlmon Marissael (2 of 3 audiocassettes), 1975 March 26; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002104888665)
  - Interview with Grace McAlmon Marissael (3 of 3 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002104888681)
- Photographs
  - Kay Boyle, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Grace McAlmon Marissael, circa 1920, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Robert McAlmon, undated (Box 1)
  - Bryher Island, undated (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes images of the Bryher Post Office, Isle of Bryher signpost, and landscapes
- Other papers
  - Colonial Terrace Hotel Register, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Photocopy of typescript of January 1921 issue of Contact, 1978 (Box 1)
    Includes 1978 November 2 letter from Heinemann to Robert McAlmon
  - Clippings on other writers, 1963-1977 (Box 1)
  - Notes, undated (Box 1)